It was all set for
me to be adopted at
birth by a
lawyer and his wife.
Except that
when I popped out,
they decided at the
last minute that they
really wanted a girl.
So my parents, who
were on a waiting
list, got a call
in the middle of the
night asking,
We've got an
unexpected baby boy.
Do you want him?
They said, of course.
My biological mother
found out later that
my mother had
never graduated from
college and that
my father had never
graduated
from high school.
She refused to sign
the final adoption
papers. She only
relented a few months
later when my
parents promised that I
would go to college.
This was the
start in my life.
And 17 years later,
I did go to college.
But I naively chose
a college that was
almost as
expensive as Stanford.
And all of my
working class parents'
savings were being
spent on my college
tuition.
After six months,
I couldn't see
the value in it.
I had no idea what I
wanted to do with my
life and no idea how
college was going to
help me
figure it out.
And here I was
spending all the money my
parents had saved
their entire life.
So I decided to
drop out and trust that
it would all
work out okay.
It was pretty
scary at the time,
but looking back, it
was one of the best
decisions I
ever made.
The
minute I dropped out,
I could stop taking
the required classes
that didn't
interest me and begin
dropping in on the
ones that looked far
more interesting.
It wasn't
all romantic.
I didn't have
a dorm room,
so I slept on the
floor in friends'
rooms. I returned
Coke bottles for the
five -cent
deposits to buy food with.
And I would walk
the seven miles across
town every Sunday
night to get one good
meal a week at the
Hare Krishna temple.
I loved it.
And much of what
I stumbled into by
following my
curiosity and intuition
turned out to be
priceless later on.
Let me give
you one example.
Reed College at that
time offered perhaps
the best
calligraphy instruction in the
country.
Throughout the campus,
every poster, every
label on every drawer
was beautifully
hand -calligraphed.
Because I had
dropped out and didn't have
to take the
normal classes,
I decided to take a
calligraphy class to
learn how to do this.
I learned about
serif and sans -serif
typefaces, about
varying the amount of
space between
different letter
combinations,
about what makes great
typography great.
It was
beautiful, historical,
artistically subtle
in a way that science
can't capture.
And I found
it fascinating.
None of this had
even a hope of any
practical
application in my life.
But ten years
later, when we were
designing the first
Macintosh computer,
it all came
back to me.
And we designed it
all into the Mac.
It was the first
computer with beautiful
typography. If I had
never dropped in on
that single
course in college,
the Mac would have
never had multiple
typefaces or
proportionally spaced fonts.
And since Windows
just copied the Mac,
it's likely that
no personal computer
would have
them. If I had
never dropped out,
I would have never
dropped in on that
calligraphy class.
And personal
computers might not have the
wonderful
typography that they do.
Of course, it was
impossible to connect
the dots looking
forward when I was in
college. But
it was very,
very clear looking
backwards ten years
later. Again, you
can't connect the dots
looking forward.
You can only
connect them looking
backwards. So you
have to trust that the
dots will somehow
connect in your future.
You have to
trust in something.
Your gut, destiny,
life, karma, whatever.
Because believing
that the dots will
connect down the
road will give you the
confidence to follow
your heart even when
it leads you off
the well -worn path.
And that will make
all the difference.
My second story is
about love and loss.
I was lucky.
I found what I loved
to do early in life.
Waz and I started
Apple in my parents'
garage when I was 20.
We worked hard.
And in 10 years,
Apple had grown from
just the two of us
in a garage into a $2
billion company
with over 4 ,000
employees. We'd just
released our finest
creation, the
Macintosh, a year earlier.
And I'd
just turned 30.
And then I got fired.
How can you get
fired from a company you
started? Well,
as Apple grew,
we hired someone
who I thought was very
talented to run
the company with me.
And for the
first year or so,
things went well.
But then our visions of
the future
began to diverge.
And eventually, we
had a falling out.
When we did, our
board of directors sided
with him. And so
at 30, I was out.
And very
publicly out.
What had been the
focus of my entire
adult life
was going to be